<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fabian Ehlert</title>
    <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fabian Ehlert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 14:57:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.fabianehlert.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 14:57:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Fabian. I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate mobile App Developer and Designer based in Germany.
I love creating Apps that are simply unique and feature an astonishing user experience evoked by a one of a kind user interface and code coded to the edge of perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-me:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Contact me!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to ask me! You would like to drink some coffee or tea with me? Just ask! Because asking has a tremendous power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@fabianehlert.com&#34;&gt;hello@fabianehlert.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Am I going to switch?</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 14:57:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/switching/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While seeking for an easy way to compose blog posts and also showing my portfolio I bumped into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hugo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
I created my previous website with Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Muse app. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to learn and gives me a lot of different options to create my website. But I still feel it&amp;rsquo;s too hard to deal with. I&amp;rsquo;m just not able to instantly publish my ideas as I always have to deal with formatting the text, moving around text boxes and other elements. It just seems to static. Okay, maybe I just haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out yet how to properly set it up for a more dynamic usage but anyways it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. It&amp;rsquo;s not intuitive enough for me and I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend the time learning Muse before I can publish content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-am-i-looking-for:c3482be23f6832233584a447a06df954&#34;&gt;What am I looking for?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a tool that is capable of interpreting markdown (Hugo is ;) 👍) and that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require me to set up a lot and is easy to maintain. For me it is all about the content. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of time dealing with stuff that prevents me from directly putting out my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daqo iExcellence App</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/iExcellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/iExcellence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An iOS and Android App I developed for the chinese electronics company Daqo based in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.de/maps/place/Nanjing,+Jiangsu,+China/@32.0995425,118.457561,10z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x35b58c9b668dcd83:0x8ffbb60b79df1b06!8m2!3d32.060255!4d118.796877&#34;&gt;Nanjing, Jiangsu&lt;/a&gt; while working at UVB-Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a team of three, working on a Windows Phone App, iOS and Android App (that was me) and the backend solution. The project itself evolved quickly after a Skype call between me and the head of UVB-Data who was visiting the Daqo headquarters in China at this time.
&lt;br&gt;It was my first client-based work which meant I also got to know a new concept of working together in a team with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(software_development)&#34;&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to that I learned working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git_(software)&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internationalization_and_localization&#34;&gt;localizing&lt;/a&gt; content, structuring and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_normalization&#34;&gt;normalizing databases&lt;/a&gt; for scale and working with different map providers at one time due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Restrictions_on_geographic_data_in_China&#34;&gt;governmental restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on the internet in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot1&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot2&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AKG Bensheim iOS App</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/AKG/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/AKG/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An App I developed to help the students at my school getting through their schooldays more easily. The core feature of it is the substitution plan with whose implementation I spent the biggest part of the development time reducing it to the most important information students need and also making it easily readable. Besides that students can also view upcoming appointments, what food will be served in the cafeteria and schedule homework tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;re viewing here is the first major project I have ever worked on now in it&amp;rsquo;s fourth major release. With this project I got to know Objective-C and the whole iOS SDK and ecosystem and ultimately brought me to what I love doing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://appstore.com/akgbensheim&#34;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;You can also check out the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabianehlert/AKG-Bensheim-iOS&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The substitution plan shows cancelled lessons etc. Every user can select his or her class and courses to see only relevant information.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot1&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detail-view shows additional information such as remarks. It can be dismissed just by flicking it away with your finger. If you try it out you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that it behaves physically accurate.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot2&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu. The center of navigation to quickly get you where you want to be. It follows a basic &amp;ldquo;Navigation-Drawer&amp;rdquo; concept with the menu lying underneath the selected view. It can be opened by swiping over the view that lies on top of it.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>