<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fabian Ehlert</title>
    <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fabian Ehlert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.fabianehlert.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Your struggle is hard. I know.</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/struggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/struggling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been in a situation where you felt just terrible, you were lost in bad thoughts and you were trying to compensate and making it all up by desperately trying to convince yourself that you are not struggling as bad as you think and telling the higher instance of yourself that bazillions of people on planet earth would be in a worse position than you?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Well you possibly have experienced something like that in person and I would like you to stop thinking with this pattern.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Because this way you&amp;rsquo;re only playing down your feelings and not taking yourself seriously. I personally think that it is absolutely right and even necessary to take your struggle seriously as subjectively it&amp;rsquo;s as hard as it can possibly get for you right now. And you deserve to be taken seriously by yourself and others as it is totally human to struggle and I probably couldn&amp;rsquo;t write it down any better than &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ashfurrow&#34;&gt;Ash Furrow&lt;/a&gt; did in his blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://ashfurrow.com/blog/normalizing-struggle/&#34;&gt;Normalizing Struggle&lt;/a&gt;.
So I want you to know that whoever you are, wherever you live and whatever you do, if you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with something and feeling bad, don&amp;rsquo;t play it down. Everybody struggles and that includes you! If you think it&amp;rsquo;s hard, it definitely is. But it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be okay!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s going on at dub dub?</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/supdubdub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/supdubdub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Wide Developers Conference. Probably the most attractive conference in the iOS, watchOS, macOS and tvOS community for years held annually in beautiful San Francisco. And that goes for me too. I have been wanting to attend for years already but never got a ticket. The demand for tickets is so strong, Apple had to start giving out tickets with a lottery system and about 5000 people were lucky and had the chance of buying a ticket for 1599$. I again didn&amp;rsquo;t get one. This year however I went to San Francisco anyways.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Although I cannot attend WWDC, it&amp;rsquo;s been a great decision so far! It&amp;rsquo;s really not about the conference, it&amp;rsquo;s rather a gigantic socializing event taking place throughout the whole week where thousands of people from around the globe gather together, communicate and exchange their knowledge regardless of their experience, age and so on.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The side-events organized by known companies such as Twitter, lyft and Realm are really what makes that possible. All of them are free to attend and it&amp;rsquo;s a quite unique experience visiting the headquarters of these companies and getting to know the spirit behind their work at least a little. Ironically we took an Uber to get to the lyft HQ 😁&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../assets/supdubdub-twitter.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter&#34; style=&#34;width: 700px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there are many events organized by the community like the &amp;ldquo;WWDC hike&amp;rdquo; where we hiked about six miles along the coast of San Francisco. Everyone was free to join and that&amp;rsquo;s where most of us first met during the dub dub week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../assets/supdubdub-hike.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;WWDC Hike&#34; style=&#34;width: 700px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how many great and inspiring people you can meet in such a short amount of time and how it pushes yourself forward when sharing your ideas and thoughts with others. There&amp;rsquo;s so much talent in the community and everyone is open to you! That truly impresses me 🙇&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming a crisis</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/overcomingacrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/overcomingacrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s something we all experience from time to time though we tend not to admit it. When I was a child my parents were somehow demonizing and making fun of it giving me the perspective everything would be perfect. And so reality gives you an even harder kick in your stomach when you yourself plunge into a deep crisis and realize that everything is not perfectly working out as you had always been told and expected it.
&lt;br&gt;I am not talking about some crisis you experience as a child like when someone pops one of the balloons your parents just bought you though at that time it might have seemed like the worst experience in a life-time but that is totally okay. I am talking about that kind of crisis that makes you feel like everything you once believed to be the most important part in your life is falling apart or gone already, nothing feels like it’s worth living anymore, you decay into indifference and apathy and you only want to lock yourself into your room and be alone. It is hard. That is no question. If you see yourself ever having felt like that before you also know that everything anybody is telling you under these circumstances feels useless. You feel like it just cannot help you and you would be caught in your desperate situation.
&lt;br&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s how I feel right now. In the exact moment of writing down these words. Well not that much anymore. I definitely felt exactly like it till a couple of days ago. But what happened that changed my feelings to the better?
&lt;br&gt;As the title already anticipates it, you will always overcome any kind of crisis. It just takes time. I always told myself knowing that other people suffer similarly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help me and I still think that&amp;rsquo;s true. Being told that other people have similar struggles when feeling terrible doesn&amp;rsquo;t change your feelings. At least not mine. But while &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; knowing that other people suffer similarly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help in this case, talking with these people and discussing your feelings indeed does! Not only knowing &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; but also &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; someone suffers and deals with it is an important difference which helps you getting your mind clear. It&amp;rsquo;s the feeling of being understood by someone who is going through or already went through something you&amp;rsquo;re going through right now that cheers you up because you sympathize with the other person and this can encourage you to see that you&amp;rsquo;re not trapped in any kind of desperate situation but you&amp;rsquo;re indeed free to do something about it!
&lt;br&gt;If you believe there is no one you could talk to or you even believe you would just bore someone when expressing your feelings, I can tell you that you are wrong! There is always somebody who is interested in how you feel. It is just totally human. Be it someone close to you or even more distant. You just have to show the courage to accept and talk about your feelings and stop gobbling them up like some disgusting junk food.
&lt;br&gt;In my experience the process isn’t linear at all. I suffer setbacks from time to time as well especially in these first days but in the end it will all turn out good! Trust me.
&lt;br&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s only one small part of dealing with and overcoming a crisis but a highly important if not the most important step of drawing yourself out of your crisis and getting yourself back on track and start enjoy being a human being again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 14:57:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Fabian. I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate mobile App Developer and Designer based in Germany.
I love creating Apps that are simply unique and feature an astonishing user experience evoked by a one of a kind user interface and code coded to the edge of perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-me&#34;&gt;Contact me!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to ask me! You would like to drink some coffee or tea with me? Just ask! Because asking has a tremendous power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@fabianehlert.com&#34;&gt;hello@fabianehlert.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Am I going to switch?</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 14:57:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/post/switching/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While seeking for an easy way to compose blog posts and also showing my portfolio I bumped into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hugo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
I created my previous website with Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Muse app. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to learn and gives me a lot of different options to create my website. But I still feel it&amp;rsquo;s too hard to deal with. I&amp;rsquo;m just not able to instantly publish my ideas as I always have to deal with formatting the text, moving around text boxes and other elements. It just seems to static. Okay, maybe I just haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out yet how to properly set it up for a more dynamic usage but anyways it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. It&amp;rsquo;s not intuitive enough for me and I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend the time learning Muse before I can publish content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-am-i-looking-for&#34;&gt;What am I looking for?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a tool that is capable of interpreting markdown (Hugo is ;) 👍) and that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require me to set up a lot and is easy to maintain. For me it is all about the content. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of time dealing with stuff that prevents me from directly putting out my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daqo iExcellence App</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/iExcellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/iExcellence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An iOS and Android App I developed for the chinese electronics company Daqo based in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.de/maps/place/Nanjing,+Jiangsu,+China/@32.0995425,118.457561,10z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x35b58c9b668dcd83:0x8ffbb60b79df1b06!8m2!3d32.060255!4d118.796877&#34;&gt;Nanjing, Jiangsu&lt;/a&gt; while working at UVB-Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a team of three, working on a Windows Phone App, iOS and Android App (that was me) and the backend solution. The project itself evolved quickly after a Skype call between me and the head of UVB-Data who was visiting the Daqo headquarters in China at this time.
&lt;br&gt;It was my first client-based work which meant I also got to know a new concept of working together in a team with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(software_development)&#34;&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to that I learned working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git_(software)&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internationalization_and_localization&#34;&gt;localizing&lt;/a&gt; content, structuring and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_normalization&#34;&gt;normalizing databases&lt;/a&gt; for scale and working with different map providers at one time due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Restrictions_on_geographic_data_in_China&#34;&gt;governmental restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on the internet in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot1&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot2&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AKG Bensheim iOS App</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/AKG/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/AKG/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An App I developed to help the students at my school getting through their schooldays more easily. The core feature of it is the substitution plan with whose implementation I spent the biggest part of the development time reducing it to the most important information students need and also making it easily readable. Besides that students can also view upcoming appointments, what food will be served in the cafeteria and schedule homework tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;re viewing here is the first major project I have ever worked on now in it&amp;rsquo;s fourth major release. With this project I got to know Objective-C and the whole iOS SDK and ecosystem and ultimately brought me to what I love doing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://appstore.com/akgbensheim&#34;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;You can also check out the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabianehlert/AKG-Bensheim-iOS&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The substitution plan shows cancelled lessons etc. Every user can select his or her class and courses to see only relevant information.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot1&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detail-view shows additional information such as remarks. It can be dismissed just by flicking it away with your finger. If you try it out you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that it behaves physically accurate.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot2&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu. The center of navigation to quickly get you where you want to be. It follows a basic &amp;ldquo;Navigation-Drawer&amp;rdquo; concept with the menu lying underneath the selected view. It can be opened by swiping over the view that lies on top of it.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>