<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Fabian Ehlert</title>
    <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Fabian Ehlert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daqo iExcellence App</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/iExcellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/iExcellence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An iOS and Android App I developed for the chinese electronics company Daqo based in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.de/maps/place/Nanjing,+Jiangsu,+China/@32.0995425,118.457561,10z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x35b58c9b668dcd83:0x8ffbb60b79df1b06!8m2!3d32.060255!4d118.796877&#34;&gt;Nanjing, Jiangsu&lt;/a&gt; while working at UVB-Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a team of three, working on a Windows Phone App, iOS and Android App (that was me) and the backend solution. The project itself evolved quickly after a Skype call between me and the head of UVB-Data who was visiting the Daqo headquarters in China at this time.
&lt;br&gt;It was my first client-based work which meant I also got to know a new concept of working together in a team with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(software_development)&#34;&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to that I learned working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git_(software)&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internationalization_and_localization&#34;&gt;localizing&lt;/a&gt; content, structuring and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_normalization&#34;&gt;normalizing databases&lt;/a&gt; for scale and working with different map providers at one time due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Restrictions_on_geographic_data_in_China&#34;&gt;governmental restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on the internet in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot1&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot2&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../iexcellence-screen3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AKG Bensheim iOS App</title>
      <link>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/AKG/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fabianehlert.com/projects/AKG/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An App I developed to help the students at my school getting through their schooldays more easily. The core feature of it is the substitution plan with whose implementation I spent the biggest part of the development time reducing it to the most important information students need and also making it easily readable. Besides that students can also view upcoming appointments, what food will be served in the cafeteria and schedule homework tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;re viewing here is the first major project I have ever worked on now in it&amp;rsquo;s fourth major release. With this project I got to know Objective-C and the whole iOS SDK and ecosystem and ultimately brought me to what I love doing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://appstore.com/akgbensheim&#34;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;You can also check out the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabianehlert/AKG-Bensheim-iOS&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The substitution plan shows cancelled lessons etc. Every user can select his or her class and courses to see only relevant information.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot1&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detail-view shows additional information such as remarks. It can be dismissed just by flicking it away with your finger. If you try it out you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that it behaves physically accurate.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot2&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu. The center of navigation to quickly get you where you want to be. It follows a basic &amp;ldquo;Navigation-Drawer&amp;rdquo; concept with the menu lying underneath the selected view. It can be opened by swiping over the view that lies on top of it.
&lt;img src=&#34;../akg-screen3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>